♪♪
It's a line drive
to center field.
Hey, I know... we can go over
to Skipper's and see his new dog.
Well, what happened
to his last one?
Ah, it died.
The way I figure,
somebody poisoned it.
Probably. That dog was mean.
And he throws him
out at home plate.
I say we go mess around
at my Uncle Bernie's store.
Nah, he'll ask us to work.
Well, it's about time somebody
in your family had a job.
Hey!
You want it?
Go get it.
I was kidding, you idiot.
No, you're the idiot, Gary.
Somebody shot him.
I wonder who he is.
Look at his arm.
We'd better go get the sheriff.
- All right.
- Down here.
- Where is it?
- Right there.
He's over here.
Well?
He's gone.
He was right here.
Gone, my eye. There
never was a body here.
Now you kids listen to me.
I'm tired of you
playing these pranks.
The next time this happens,
I'm going to arrest you all.
You hear me?
But, Sheriff...
This time, I'm just
going to tell your parents.
I hope they blister
your hind ends.
Sheriff, wait.
Right. He was right there.
Mr. Matlock?
Your Honor.
Before we begin, I'd like
to say what an honor it is
to have an attorney of your reputation
and skill here in small claims court.
Well, thank you, Your Honor.
You remember Billy Joe Pollard?
Well, yes.
He was accused of killing his
business partner and he didn't do it.
And you proved it.
- He's my cousin.
- Oh.
Okay, that's it.
I want a change of venue.
Pardon?
Well, you and him...
You're practically related.
I can't get a fair
trial in this court.
This isn't a trial. This is
a small claims hearing.
I'll hear both sides of the story and
make an impartial, objective decision.
Now, is that clear,
Mrs. Maloney?
Yes, sir.
Mr. Matlock, you may proceed.
Yes, Your Honor.
I needed a refrigerator to put in my
garage for soda and stuff like that, see?
And I bought Mrs. Maloney's.
Well, the second day I had
it, I heard this terrible noise,
and I ran out to the garage,
and the smoke was just pouring
out of the back of this refrigerator.
The second day... And
I want my money back.
Okay, Mrs. Maloney, your turn.
Okay.
This bozo here
shows up with the ad
that I pinned on the bulletin
board at the supermarket.
He looked at my refrigerator,
said he wanted it, and he bought it.
That's it.
The refrigerator was
running when you bought it?
Oh, like a clock.
The cord was a little frayed.
I told him to get a new one.
- Did you get a new cord?
- No, I taped it up.
You can't tape a cord
that's frayed from end to...
Your Honor, if I'd known he
was going to be such a jerk,
I wouldn't have loaded that
refrigerator onto his rent-a-truck.
You let Mrs. Maloney
load the truck?
I have a bad back.
Anything else, Mrs. Maloney?
Yes, sir.
That refrigerator
was built in 1962.
It's a collector's item.
Even broke it's worth something.
1962?
Mr. Matlock, how much did
you pay for the refrigerator?
67 dollars and 48 cents.
67?
You came to court for $67.48?
Certainly.
You charged my cousin,
Billy Joe Pollard, $100,000.
- Well, that's my fee.
- He borrowed most of it from me.
- Well, I...
- Mr. Matlock,
anybody who buys a 1962 refrigerator
with a frayed cord which he doesn't replace
deserves what he gets.
- But, Your Honor...
- I find for the defendant Mrs. Maloney.
- Next case.
- But, Your Honor...
Dismissed.
Nice try.
- Ben?
- Hey.
Hi. Ready to be taken to dinner?
Yeah.
Oh, is that you?
Yeah. Eighth
birthday... first bike.
Is that your family?
Yeah, cousin Bink, Cousin
Jane, Uncle Roy, Uncle Joe,
Great-Aunt Kate, my mom,
Grandma, Grandpa, and Aunt Elsie.
She called me today.
- From Mt. Harlan?
- Yeah.
Everybody in this picture who's
still alive lives in Mt. Harlan but me.
Did Aunt Elsie call
you with bad news?
Oh, no, no.
She invited me
to a family reunion;
part of Mt. Harlan's
bicentennial celebration.
- How fun.
- Yeah.
I'm not going.
You're not?
No.
They don't like me.
Why?
Well, after I graduated
from law school,
everybody just figured that I was
going to come back to Mt. Harlan
and be the town lawyer.
They even got me up a
shingle... The town lawyer...
And when I went to Atlanta,
they all thought I'd let them down,
and the last time I was there,
they still felt the same way.
- How long ago was that?
- Twenty years.
Oh, Ben, that's ancient history.
Who'd carry a grudge
for over 20 years?
Well, I bet everybody who is old enough to
remember still does... all but Aunt Elsie.
I know one that still
does... Billy Lewis.
I dated his sister, and he got
mad, and he's been mad ever since.
He didn't want you
dating his sister?
No, that was all right.
That was all right, but she
started looking for wedding rings.
Oh, so you dropped her?
I got another girl.
And then I went off to college
and went with another girl and
another girl and Billy got mad.
- Hmm, a real Don Juan.
- Well...
So whatever happened
to Billy's sister?
Lucy.
She's mad, too.
Last time I heard, she's
still single and lives with Billy.
That's why he's mad.
Elsie wants me to bring you.
Me?
Well, I write to
her all the time,
and I guess I write to her a lot
about you, and she wants to meet you.
- Well, I'm flattered.
- Hmm.
- And I do have some time coming.
- Mm-hmm.
Of course, I wouldn't know anybody
there except you and Aunt Elsie.
Oh, and Lucy, if
you'll introduce me.
- You want to go?
- Yes.
Well...
It's a long high
fly into left field.
Come on, Gary, let's go.
Let's get something to eat.
And it's a line drive
right into his glove.
- Noel?
- Max.
Noel Ferguson.
Get out here.
- Hey.
Is this what city slickers
are wearing these days?
This is what
writers are wearing.
I liked your book.
Who wrote it for you?
I'm glad you did.
Who read it to you?
Whoo.
Watch the glasses.
It takes me back.
So what are you doing here?
Oh, another book.
The first one was a
boy's memory of home,
and this one is about a man
who goes home again, or tries to.
It's no secret the man is me.
So, here I am, just chasing
my book, asking questions.
People are talking to you?
I hope so.
I think the only thing people in this
town like better than holding a grudge
is gossiping about each other.
You guys remember that
time when we were about 12
and we saw that guy get killed?
Hi, guys.
Hey.
- It was hot in the car.
- Aw.
Wow. So what we heard is true.
You and Noel are...?
Living together.
So have you seen
Russ Gifford yet?
I stopped being his girl
three years ago, Gary.
It was just a question.
Come on. Let's go
get something to eat.
Max is starving,
and I haven't had cornmeal-fried
catfish since I left this town.
So are you really going to write
about that time when we were kids?
Well, Gary, we saw
somebody get killed,
and it was covered up
like it never happened.
I mean, it sounds
like a story to me.
- Well...
- I'm just trying to write a book.
That's not what the
town is going to think.
Noel, your car.
See what I mean?
Here comes Ben.
Everybody, come
on! They're here!
Hey, there he is.
Oh, it's been so long.
Oh, Aunt Elsie.
Oh, excuse me, Julie.
This is my Aunt Elsie.
- Hi.
- Everybody, this is my friend Julie March.
Harley, Cousin Harley.
Ben, seems like there's something
about you in the paper every week.
Don't believe
everything you read.
If you're not the spitting
image of my nephew Pat.
I'm his son Max. Max Carter.
Oh, Max.
What on earth are we all
standing around out here for?
You all help him with the bags, and
the rest of you all go on back inside.
- You must be tired.
- Oh, not at all.
This is for you.
Well, thank you.
You're just as sweet
as Ben said you were,
but he didn't tell me
you were so pretty.
Oh.
I can get them, Harley.
Well, as I live and
breathe, Billy Lewis.
Welcome back to Mt. Harlan, Ben.
What's it been? Forty years?
Since I've been
back? Oh, more like 20.
Come on, everybody. Come on,
there's pie and lemonade inside.
Lucy says hello.
Hello to Lucy.
You're looking good, Billy.
- Yeah?
- Yeah. You haven't aged a minute.
Everybody, come on.
There's nothing worse than
cold pie and warm lemonade.
Jackass.
Times sure change,
don't they, Lucas?
Fifteen years ago, you were a
short order cook over in Lumpkin,
and now look at you.
Suddenly you've got this place.
I heard you paid 35,000 for
it and another 8 to fix it up.
About that.
Well, that's a lot
of money, Lucas.
You've been gone too long, Noel.
You forget that people around
here don't ask personal questions.
Don't answer them, either.
What's personal about it? It's
just an American success story.
You know, local boy makes good.
I keep my personal business
and finances to myself, Noel.
Hey, Lucas. Give me a beer.
You've got no business
coming back here.
It's still a free country, Russ.
You just wanted to show
everyone you stole my girl.
I don't steal.
And if I did, I'd steal
things, not people.
Let's step outside.
What's the matter? Slashing
my tires wasn't enough for you?
I'm just a hick. You should
be able to handle me easy.
Outside.
Take a hike, greaseball.
Come on.
Let me go!
Cut it out.
You guys got a score to settle,
you take it outside, you understand?
Out! Out of my bar!
You, too. Out of here.
Oh, come on,
Lucas, he started it.
I don't care. What
the hell you looking at?
- Nothing.
- Out of here.
Now, this won't take a second.
Take it easy. It won't
hurt. You've already laid it.
Ow!
How would you like to be soup?
Heh.
Oh, hello, Billy.
Elsie wants eggs.
I hate dealing with chickens, and
I hate chicken coops. They stink.
Chickens are the same as
always, and it's the same coop.
Ah, give me the bucket.
Billy, we've got to talk.
We've got to settle
things between us.
Glad you feel that way, Ben.
I need some money.
The tires on my pickup are
bald, payment's due on my tractor,
and my gall bladder's
got to come out.
So how about it?
Well, Billy, I just can't.
Why not?
I hear you're doing real good in
Atlanta, so I guess you can spare it.
Well, I'm not that rich, Billy.
I'm not asking for much.
A set of tires for my truck, a
couple of payments on my tractor,
and take out my gall bladder.
Maybe a couple
of dresses for Lucy.
Dropping her the way you did it
might make her feel better, poor thing.
Could we go outside in
the air and talk about this?
Yes or no, right now.
You drive a hard bargain, Billy.
So when are you and
Benjamin getting married?
Well, I don't know.
Oh, but you are getting
married, aren't you?
I don't know that, either.
Well, you two are sharing a bed
up there in Atlanta, aren't you?
Oh, honey, asking for separate
rooms was real thoughtful,
but it didn't fool
me for a minute.
Aunt Elsie, believe me...
Did you know that most geniuses
are fathered by men over 50?
- Uh, no.
- And I was reading in People magazine
that women a lot older than you
are are having babies every day.
So how many do you figure
you and Ben are going to have?
Well, we... Anybody home?
- Noel.
- Hey.
Oh, honey, Max told
me you were in town.
Oh, well, it's real
important that I talk to him.
Is he home from work yet?
No, he's up in Valdosta. He won't
be back till day after tomorrow.
Oh, perfect timing.
Julie March, Ben Matlock,
this is Noel Ferguson.
- Hi.
- One of Max' oldest and dearest friends.
Ben is the famous lawyer,
as I'm sure you know,
- and Julie is his bride-to-be.
- What?
Oh, and of course you
already know Billy Lewis.
You used to date
Billy's sister, didn't you?
- Yes.
- Well, what happened?
Dropped her like a hot potato.
I went to law school.
But not before you had a good fling
with old man Rolland's daughter Flossie.
Remember when old man
Rolland caught you and Flossie
in the hayloft of the barn?
We were playing hide-and-seek.
At 17?
We weren't doing anything.
Yeah.
Or the time he caught you behind
the church during Sunday school?
We were talking about
the Bible... Revelations.
Flossie was revealing.
Behind the church?
Your sister never did
marry, did she, Billy?
Noel.
Nope, never married.
She lives with me.
It's been a real good
life living with Lucy.
I'll see you all later.
Ben.
- It was very nice to meet the both of you.
- Mm-hmm.
And I will see you
at the bicentennial.
Well, why don't you two lovebirds
take a little walk or something, huh?
What a good idea.
Come on, lovebird.
What the hell's been
going on in here?
Here you go, my friend.
- Okay.
- 4 and 5.
- All right. Thank you, Bernie.
- You bet.
How you doing, Bernie?
Noel. Hey, good to see you.
Yeah, you, too.
Look, is Gary around?
Making deliveries. Won't
be back till maybe, oh, 6.
Damn.
Listen, can I borrow a piece of
that paper and your pen for a minute?
- Sure. Help yourself.
- Thank you.
Heard about what
happened at the tavern.
The fight? Russ started it.
You're asking for trouble.
I'm just writing a book.
Listen, could you make sure Gary
gets this as soon as he comes back in?
- Sure.
- Thank you.
- Noel?
- Yeah?
Hanging people's dirty laundry
out is a pitiful way to make a dollar.
Vince Henry's still mad at me.
He's the one that paid for
the shingle the town gave me
when I graduated law school.
Did you and Lucy go to Vince's?
Sometimes.
We didn't do anything.
Nothing?
Well, we kissed.
Oh, behind the church.
I was 17. Nearly grown.
- Come on, let's go there.
- Where?
- Behind the church.
- No, let's go to Vince's.
- Then behind the church?
- We'll see.
Hello, Mrs. Sylvester.
Is your husband in?
No, he's not.
I don't see any
real reason to panic
till we find out
exactly what's go...
Hello, Mr. Sylvester.
If you've got a few minutes, I'd
like to talk to you about something.
You, too, Doc.
We're not going to answer
your questions, Noel.
The only reason you're here is to
hurt this town and everybody in it.
I'm not here to hurt anybody.
I'm just doing my work,
just gathering background.
Gather it in some
other town, Noel.
No, I don't think so.
When I start something,
I like to finish it.
It's a bad habit I picked
up from my father.
Pam?
Honey, is that you?
Hey, Buck. How you doing?
Hey, Sheriff. What
can I do for you?
You're under arrest for the
murder of Noel Ferguson.
Wait a minute. I didn't
kill Noel Ferguson.
I don't know what you're
talking... This ain't me.
I didn't have anything
to do with Noel Ferguson.
In the car, son.
- But, Sheriff...
- In the car, son.
- Ben Matlock?
- Yes, sir.
Somebody wants to see
you down at the jailhouse.
Hello, Mr. Matlock.
I heard you were in town.
I've got to have
somebody defend me.
- For what?
- I didn't kill Noel Ferguson.
Noel?
Yeah. Somebody
stabbed him with my knife.
Noel's dead?
When I left for
work this morning,
that knife was on my back
porch where it always is,
and I don't know how it
got into that motel room.
Someone must've stolen
it. And I was at work all day.
Well... almost all day.
At 4:15 I got a call from someone
saying he was a friend of Noel's.
Said that Noel wanted
me to meet him at 5:00
in the orchard off
Candyline Road
so that we could... settle
our differences in private.
So I took off work at 4:30, and then I
drove out there... only he never showed.
I waited till 5:30,
and then I drove back.
Well, did anybody see you?
No.
You have any idea
who it was that called?
I just figured it was one of the
guys that Noel always hung out with.
Your father used to do that.
What?
Run his fingers through his
hair when he was agitated.
Are you going to
defend me, Mr. Matlock?
Oh, son, I'm just going to be in town
a short while, just for the bicentennial.
There are a lot of lawyers in
Mt. Harlan, and it just wouldn't...
Well, I'll tell you what.
I'm going to have
to take me a...
A walk and think about this.
See, the thing is I'm
just here on vacation...
I mean, for the bicentennial...
And if I defend Russ Gifford,
well, I'll be here for
the duration of the trial.
And then, too, I'm not the
most popular person in town.
I mean, a Mt. Harlan jury could
take their dislike of me out on Russ.
I mean, not meaning to
or not even knowing it, see.
And then, too,
he can't afford me.
Those are all reasons why
you shouldn't take the case.
Any reasons why you should?
Well, I think the
boy's innocent.
The other two lawyers in
town, Ed and Charles Reese...
Ed's recovering
from a mild stroke,
and Charles, it took him
nine times to pass the bar.
Sounds like he doesn't have
much of a chance without you.
Well, I don't know.
Do you want to
know what I think?
First, this isn't the big city
with a loaded court calendar.
Russ Gifford's going
to come to trial quickly.
Second, tell the jury that you're afraid
you'll bias them against your client.
Mt. Harlan may not like you,
but the people are
decent and honest,
and they're going to bend
over backwards to be fair.
Third, the fee...
Can Russ afford a local lawyer?
I guess.
Then just charge him what
you would have charged him
if you'd never left Mt. Harlan.
- Now...
- You can afford it, and he can afford it.
And maybe you'll stop feeling
guilty about abandoning the town.
I don't feel guilty.
I'll stay here with
you till the trial is over.
You will?
I've never seen a bluer
sky or lovelier roses,
and the company's not too bad.
We could go behind the church
again or find that man's barn,
or Aunt Elsie said we
could use just one...
- Julie.
- Room.
Oh, I'm sorry. I didn't know
anybody else was in here.
Who are you?
I'm Ben Matlock. And you're?
Pam Arnold.
- Ben Matlock?
- Yes.
I'm handling Russ
Gifford's case.
His father was an
old friend of mine.
How did you get in here?
Oh, I talked to the manager and had
him let me in so I could get my things.
Oh, you're... you
were Noel's girlfriend.
Yeah. And before that,
I was Russ' girlfriend.
That's what started
this godawful mess.
Uh, was this Noel's?
- The laptop?
- Yeah.
Yeah, he kept all his
notes for his book in there.
Did it always have
all these cracks in it?
No. What happened?
Looks like somebody
went at it with a hammer.
Does it work?
Oh!
No.
Did he ever talk to
you about his book?
All the time.
He said he was
doing background on it.
Did he say that he
had found anything?
He might have.
Well, if Russ didn't kill him,
then somebody who is afraid Noel
was about to blow the whistle on him did.
You don't think Russ killed him?
No, I don't think he did.
Good, because I've
known Russ my whole life.
I know he couldn't
do something like this.
Gary, I told you
to take the day off.
I'd just as soon
work, Uncle Bernie.
It will help me keep
my mind off Noel.
Well, then, you can round up old
Ned here four bags of sweet feed.
All right.
Drive up. Pick it up around
back. Gary will get you loaded.
Right.
Gary,
Noel stopped by
and left you this note.
Where'd you say this pain is?
It's right back in here.
It comes and goes.
Ooh, ooh.
Well, I hope my
insurance covers this.
You know, I've heard of doctors
billing insurance companies
for examinations never done and
for procedures never performed.
How do you suppose
they get away with that?
- Wouldn't know.
- I don't, either.
You know, Doc, you've done pretty
well for yourself in this little town.
A condo in Florida and
a yacht off Hilton Head.
Who told you that?
Noel told Pam
Arnold before he died.
I wanted to come see
you earlier about this pain,
but your office was
closed yesterday after 4:00.
You know, the day
that Noel was killed.
I was catching up
with correspondence.
I don't like this kind of
talk and these accusations.
I've known Russell
Gifford since he was 7.
When I heard you were
defending him, I, for one, was glad.
But if this is the
way you operate,
by bullying innocent people
with slanderous accusations,
shame on you, Ben Matlock.
Shame on you.
- Hey, Gary.
- Lucas.
What can I get you?
Oh, give me a cool one.
I didn't know you had a
tattoo on your left arm, Lucas.
Yeah, got it in Nam.
Can I see it?
Yeah.
You know, I saw a tattoo just like
that 15 years ago on a dead man.
- Huh.
- What's J.A.S. stand for?
My nickname in the
Army was Jasper.
I gotta go.
- Thanks.
- You bet.
- See you later.
- Mm-hmm.
It's me, and we've
got a problem.
Cousin Benjamin.
Oh, Cousin Bink.
- How's it going?
- Oh, very well.
Doing a little banking, huh?
Just hoping to have a few
words with Jack Sylvester.
Just last week, he
turned me down for a loan.
- Huh.
- All I need is a couple of hundred.
Well, Bink, you know
what Shakespeare said.
He said, "Neither a
borrower nor a lender be."
Yeah, well, I doubt if Shakespeare
ever had to dig a new septic tank.
Billy told me about that
money you loaned him, Ben.
You know, he's not even kin.
Two hundred?
Come on in.
- Mr. Matlock.
- Yes, sir.
Jack Sylvester. It's a
pleasure to meet you.
Yes, sir. You, too.
Can I get you anything?
No, thank you.
Thank you, Karen.
- Please, have a seat.
- I see.
Thanks. Well, your
wife works for you.
You don't see very much of that.
Well, maybe not in Atlanta,
but here it happens all the time.
Oh? Oh, yeah. Like
the minister and his wife.
Excuse me?
Well, doesn't Mary Lou Summons
work for Reverend Summons?
I suppose.
I heard that you and Mary Lou have
been close friends for almost a year now.
Who told you that?
From Noel Ferguson... indirectly...
Through his girlfriend Pam.
Apparently, he uncovered your friendship
while he was researching for his book.
I am not having an affair
with Mary Lou Summons.
Okay, okay.
But if you were and
everybody found out about it,
that big political future you want
would be out the window, wouldn't it?
I don't have time to answer
your hypothetical questions.
Well, here's a specific one: Where
were you between 5 and 5:30 yesterday?
Do you remember?
Mr. Matlock, I find your
questions offensive.
Well, you're not the first one.
Needless to say, if you
repeat these lies about me,
I will sue you for
everything you've got.
Well, sometimes I tell what I
know, and sometimes I don't.
It just all depends.
Benjamin, how are you doing?
Uncle Roy.
Listen, I just run into Bink,
and he told me how
you floated him that loan.
The fact is I'm a little short
of funds myself right now.
What is it? Trouble with your
septic tank or your gall bladder?
No, I've got to get a bull for
Suey May... Rent, not buy.
You see, Suey May has
never calved, and I thought...
Have you got a pen?
Not a word about
this to anybody.
Hell, I can tell you exactly
where I got the money.
I inherited it.
Oh. Hey.
And so you decided
to invest it in this place.
Always wanted to own my own bar.
Good one.
Uh, I have to
ask you... Fishing.
Fishing?
That's where I was at the time
of the murder. Rainbow Creek.
Oh. Oh.
Alone or with somebody?
Alone.
Did you get anything?
Mosquito bites and a cold.
Yeah, I know the feeling.
Well, thanks for your time.
Don't mention it.
Why are you asking
me all these questions?
Because you've been the
doctor here for almost 20 years.
You know everything
about everybody.
I wouldn't go that far.
And so what if Lucas has a
tattoo on his arm. Lots of men do.
I need to know where he got it.
Why don't you ask him?
I did. He said he got it
when he served in Vietnam.
Well, maybe that's
where he got it.
Thanks, Doc.
Ben, have you got a minute?
Hey, Harley.
Ben, I'm not comfortable
with you defending Russ.
Why is that?
We're kin, Ben.
It don't look good for me to have my
own cousin defending somebody I arrested.
Oh, well, I can understand that.
Plus, I've got to
be honest with you.
People around here think you look
at us and see a bunch of dumb hicks.
You take this case,
and they're going to think
you're meddling in our
affairs just to show us up.
No, Harley.
I think the boy is innocent, and
somebody needs to help him.
You get the cold shoulder
from the townspeople you talk to,
don't say I didn't warn you.
Ain't nothing easy,
Cousin Harley.
Even in the big city,
ain't nothing easy.
Billy.
Lucy's going to be at
the bicentennial tomorrow.
Is she?
Can't wait to see you.
Can't wait to see her.
- Ben...
- I'm not loaning you any more money.
Who said anything about money?
- Well, I just figured...
- Hell, no.
I didn't say anything
about money.
I'll just live with the pain.
As long as I can stand it.
It's a back molar,
abscessed. Got to be pulled.
Just 600.
Six hundred dollars?
You think I'm not
going to pay you back?
You dump my poor sister
who loved you more than life,
and now you think I'm some hick
who ain't going to pay you back.
Billy, $600 is a lot of money.
The dentist told me there's
poison in that abscess.
It could spread
through my whole body.
Billy.
And I'm a goner.
And who'd take care of Lucy?
Billy.
Of course, she could
probably go somewhere,
live in one of those homes.
Billy.
I'm going to give you the money.
No, it's for the best. Lucy
wouldn't want me to take it.
No. Here, I'm writing it out.
Never mind.
No. Here you go. There. There.
There.
No.
Billy.
Okay.
I don't want it.
It's against my better judgment
because you insulted me,
but I'll take it.
Thank you.
- Don't tell Lucy.
- I won't.
She'll see you at the party.
I'm looking forward to it.
I just hate this.
Go ahead. You
hardly ate any dinner.
I'm still not hungry.
Why don't I warm you up
a nice piece of pecan pie?
Coming back was
a mistake, Julie.
I should have stayed at home.
Oh, this is where you were born.
It will always be part of you,
and you'll always be part of it.
All I do around here
is make people mad.
Maybe I ought to go on back home and
let somebody else take Russell's case.
You do and I'll
never forgive you.
Well, you see how
everybody treats me.
They treat you that way because
of who you are and what you do.
They're so jealous of you, they
can't see straight, don't you know that?
- Oh, Julie.
- Well, it's true.
And I won't hear of you
going back to Atlanta
before you finish
what you started,
so stop wallowing in self-pity.
And eat your pie.
There you go.
Here.
Folks were betting
you wouldn't show up.
Buying your way through?
You do seem to be attracting
quite a bit of attention.
They're trying to figure whether to
tar and feather me now or after dessert.
Ben? Ben Matlock?
It's me... Lucy.
Oh, Lucy.
Well, you look
just like yourself.
Who's the skinny
redhead with all the teeth?
Oh, I'm sorry.
Lucy Lewis, this
is a friend of mine...
Julie March.
It's nice to meet you.
I'll bet.
Figured you'd get
yourself a big city woman.
Well, Julie doesn't
belong to me.
I'm a district attorney from
Atlanta and a colleague of Ben's.
Sure.
Waylan just got here.
Got out of bed, huh?
Keep your dance card
open, Ben. You owe me one.
Come on, Billy!
You be nice to
her. She's sensitive.
That was your
hometown sweetheart?
Julie, you have to understand.
A long time ago, she was a lot
younger, and she was prettier and thinner
and nicer, I... I think.
You could have told her
I was a district attorney.
"Julie doesn't belong to me."
I think I'll go see how they're
doing with the tar and feathers.
♪♪
♪ ...rapturous scene
that rises to my sight ♪
♪ Sweet fields
arrayed in living green ♪
♪ And rivers of delight ♪
♪ On Jordan's
stormy banks I stand ♪
♪ And cast a wishful eye ♪
♪ To Canaan's fair
and happy land ♪
♪ Where my possessions lie ♪
♪ Sweet fields
arrayed in living green ♪
♪ And rivers of delight ♪
Ben.
I just got back.
Aunt Elsie gave me the news
about Noel over the phone.
I still can't believe it.
I'm sorry. He was a good friend.
Are you going to defend Russ?
Yeah.
Maxwell. Maxwell,
welcome back, honey.
- Have you seen Gary?
- No.
Well, he told me to tell you to
call him the second you got in.
- He said it was urgent.
- Maybe I'll just go over his place.
How about if I go with you?
Sure, but you're
going to miss the party.
Oh, no, I won't. And
they won't miss me, either.
Looks like a car went
through the railing.
Oh, my God!
What?
That's Gary's truck.
- Careful.
- Yeah. Okay. Hold on.
- I got it.
- Easy.
How are you doing, son?
First I lose Noel and now Gary.
How do you think I'm doing?
Any idea how it happened?
I found this in the cab.
My guess is he got
feeling bad about Noel,
had a couple too many,
went through the rail.
You going to check
his blood-alcohol level?
Of course I'm going to
check his blood-alcohol level.
It was just a question.
You don't think I
know what I'm doing.
I'm sick and tired of everybody in
this town taking everything I say wrong.
We're sick and tired of you butting
your nose in where it doesn't belong.
Now, you go back to town
before I give you a ticket.
All right, Harley.
We're going to
settle this between us.
I've got paperwork to do.
It can wait.
You think just because we're not in
Atlanta, nobody knows what they're doing?
Bull, Harley, bull!
We survived all these years
without you in this town, Ben Matlock.
Now I've got you telling me
how to check Gary's alcohol level.
All I want is for an innocent man,
Russ, not to have to go to prison.
What makes you think I want
to convict an innocent man
just because I don't have some
big damn Harvard Law degree.
You know what it is?
Your nose is out of joint
because you're jealous.
- Jealous?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
Ben, Sheriff, both
of you come upstairs!
Hurry!
You've got to hear this. Gary
called while we were at the park.
Listen to the message he left.
Max, Gary.
It's 4:10. I'm on my way
to the park for the party.
Look, if I don't see you
there, you have got to call me.
Remember that tattoo we saw
on that dead guy 15 years ago?
Well, Noel left me a note
on the day he was killed
saying he'd seen a tattoo just
like it on Lucas Anderson's left arm.
And he was right. I saw it, too.
And when I asked Lucas
about it... Just call me.
Something weird is going on.
4:10.
That's just a half an hour before
his truck was spotted off the road.
He doesn't sound drunk.
What's all this about a tattoo?
About 15 years ago,
when we were kids,
me, Noel, and Gary were
walking through the woods
when all of a sudden
we heard a shot.
Then this man we'd never seen
before came running out of the woods,
bleeding from a
hole in his back.
He fell down and
died right in front of us.
We ran off to get the sheriff,
and by the time we got
back, the body was gone.
There never was a body. Those three
used to pull pranks on me all the time.
It wasn't a prank. It
happened, and this proves it.
The man had a tattoo on
the upper part of his left arm,
and I guess Lucas Anderson at
Anderson Tavern has one, too.
Lots of guys have tattoos.
Look at what's happened.
Noel leaves Gary a message
about the tattoo, and he gets killed.
Now, Gary leaves me a message
about it, and he gets killed.
Oh, come on. Noel got
killed because of a girl,
and Gary got killed because
he was drinking and driving.
Millions of guys
have tattoos, Max.
Guys have "Mom"
tattooed on their arms.
Girls have butterflies tattooed
on their you-know-whats.
Neither case has anything
to do with an alleged tattoo
that three kids allegedly saw on an
alleged dead man 15 damn years ago.
You could at least ask
Lucas about the tattoo.
That wouldn't hurt anything.
Lucas Anderson is a
perfectly respectable,
tax paying, law-abiding
member of the community,
and having a
tattoo is not a crime.
Now, if you'll excuse me, I
have an accident to write up.
Do you think you could draw me a
picture of that tattoo from memory?
Sure.
I'll send it to Atlanta and see
what we can come up with.
There is a fax machine
somewhere in Mt. Harlan, isn't there?
We're not that far behind
the times, Uncle Benjamin.
- You got one in your office?
- I got one in my car.
Hey.
Oh, I'd better get back to
the party. I'll see you there.
Damn it, Billy, you put that whiskey
in your pocket, and you leave it there.
You just wait till
I get you home.
♪ Come to the
church in the vale ♪
♪ No place is so
dear to my childhood ♪
I already gave.
- Ah...
- Oh, Clara.
Uh, excuse me just a minute.
I'll see you later.
You want some lemonade?
I'd love some.
You probably ought
to buy it... be cheaper.
Oh, go on.
Run over there
tomorrow, all right?
Okay, bye-bye.
- Hi.
I'm Julie March,
Ben Matlock's friend.
Ah. Karen Sylvester.
- Oh, you're the banker's wife.
- Yes.
Don't you work for
your husband, too?
Yes, I do.
It's kind of like working
for him at home...
He takes what I do for
granted, and I never get a raise.
I think I saw you walking the other
morning with a group of women.
I'd love to join you
sometime, if you don't mind.
Uh, fine.
We meet over by the
church, 6:30 a.m. to start.
Okay, 6:30.
Well, maybe we'll
see you tomorrow.
Oh, I'll be there. Thank you.
- Bye-bye.
- Bye.
Ben, what's wrong?
I'm sorry about the lemonade.
Max just gave me this.
- What's that?
- A tattoo.
What's J.A.S. stand for?
I don't know.
They're all over at
Doc's picnic table.
Oh?
Well, hello, guys.
Doc, Mr. Sylvester,
Lucas, Billy.
I guess you heard about the boy
that was killed on his way over
here this afternoon... Gary Adler.
Yeah. Terrible
thing. Just terrible.
- You all knew him?
- Well, of course we did.
Uh, you ever seen
anything like this before?
It's a tattoo.
You've got a tattoo like this
on your arm, don't you, Lucas?
Yeah. What about it?
I was just wondering if you two gentlemen
have a tattoo like this on your arm.
- Well, I certainly don't.
- Me, neither.
Would you mind rolling up your sleeves
just a little bit so we could take a look?
- I beg your pardon?
- Just take a second.
- Forget it.
- Hey, come on.
He's just asking you to roll up
your sleeve. What's the big deal?
I resent being
treated like a liar.
Come on, Doc. We
don't have to take this.
Two of my friends are
dead, and I want to know why.
Now roll up your damn sleeves.
Hey!
Wait a minute! Wait a
minute! Hold it! Hold it!
♪ Come to the church in the... ♪
Stop it now.
Okay, now stop
it, stop it, stop it.
Stop it!
Ben.
Ben. Goodness gracious.
- Does it hurt?
- Yeah.
- Here?
- Oh!
Ohh...
Why would a man your
age want to get into a fight?
I was trying to stop it, Elsie.
I guess I didn't do it right.
Martin Jensen?
Yeah. What do you need?
I understand this is your work.
You understand wrong.
Two different tattoo artists mentioned
your name when I showed this to them.
What can I tell you?
They were mistaken.
Well, you would have
done it at least 15 years ago.
Take another look. Maybe
it will come back to you.
Nope.
Well, thanks anyway.
Yeah. Sorry I couldn't help.
No problem.
What are you
working on? The rose?
No, the dragon.
Dragon?
Wonderful dragon.
It's all right.
Sheriff Wilkes, on August
17th, the day before his murder,
did you receive a telephone
call from Noel Ferguson?
Objection. Calls for hearsay.
That's not hearsay. He was
just asking if he had a call.
- Yeah, but...
- You can answer.
Yep, he called me.
Sheriff, what did he say?
I knew it. Hearsay.
Objection. Hearsay.
Did he sound excited, Harley?
He did.
Excited utterance.
Objection overruled.
What did he say?
He said his tires had been slashed
and he thought Russ Gifford done it.
- Your Honor...
- Overruled.
Continue.
I'm showing you People's Exhibit
#5 and ask for you to identify it.
That's the knife I discovered
in the decedent's chest
when I went to the murder scene.
And whose knife
is it? Do you know?
Yes, sir. The defendant,
Russ Gifford's.
- Well, how do you know that?
- Three reasons.
First, Bernie Adler remembers
selling it to him three years ago.
Objection! No foundation!
How do you know Bernie Adler
remembers selling it to him, Harley?
He told me.
Well, that's good enough for me.
Second, everybody in town's
seen that knife in Russ' possession.
Objection. Improper.
Have you ever seen that knife
in Russ' possession, Harley?
- Lots of times.
- Overruled. Go ahead.
Give me a second, Your Honor.
Just because you know everybody in town
doesn't make this evidence not hearsay.
- Sit down.
- But, Your Honor...
I said sit down!
Mr. Richardson.
Yes, sir.
So you've seen Russ
Gifford with this knife.
What makes you think he had to be
the one to kill Noel Ferguson with it?
We sent the knife to the
lab in Atlanta for analysis.
The only fingerprints
on it were Russ'.
Even a hick could
figure that out.
Hey! Hey!
Sheriff Wilkes...
Cousin Harley...
Do you know anybody who actually
saw my client stab Noel Ferguson?
No.
Do you know anybody who saw him at
or near the Motor Court that afternoon?
Not that I can find.
Did you dust the room where the
body was found for fingerprints?
I did... personally
and thoroughly.
I know it was thorough, Cousin.
Did you find my client's
fingerprints anywhere in that room?
No.
Not even on the
door or the doorknob?
No.
Don't you find it a little odd
that my client would leave his
fingerprints all over the murder weapon
and yet not leave them
anywhere else in the room?
He just didn't touch
anything else, that's all.
Uh-huh.
How about fibers?
Did you find any fibers from
the rug at my client's house
at the scene of the crime?
No.
He has a big dog.
Did you find any dog hairs
at the scene of the crime?
No.
No one saw my client anywhere
near that Motor Court that afternoon.
The only thing you have tying
my client to the murder is the knife,
which anyone could
have stolen from his house
and, wearing a pair of gloves,
used it to commit the murder.
Right, Sheriff?
Come on, Ben. Russ just got
done picking a fight with him.
No hairs. No
fibers. No witnesses.
The only thing you have tying my client
to the scene of the crime is the knife.
Isn't that right, Sheriff?
That's right, Mr. Matlock.
Thank you.
No further questions.
Found it. I guess you forgot.
Then again, it was 15 years ago.
How'd you get in here?
- The door was open.
- No, it wasn't.
It is now.
After I found this, I
made a couple of calls.
Can you imagine my surprise when I found
out that you were in prison 15 years ago?
I just want to know about the
people you did the tattoo on, Marty.
That's all.
Yeah. I got an emergency here.
Somebody just
broke into my store.
Hang on, I'll ask.
They want to know
if you're armed.
Hey, look, sorry, guys.
It was just my friend Ralph
playing a little trick on me.
Thanks anyway, though, okay?
Hamilton.
This is Marty Jensen.
I told you not to call me here.
Listen, somebody was
just here. They had a picture
of the tattoo I did on you guys.
Who was it?
He didn't introduce himself,
but he asked questions like a cop.
What kind of questions?
He wanted to know
who you guys where.
Did you tell him?
Do you think I'm nuts?
Look, the bad news
is I think he'll be back.
You there?
When was the last time
you had a vacation, Marty?
Vacations cost money, pal.
Meet me at 7 at the old
warehouse on Ashford,
and I'll have your
traveling money.
- Okay.
- I'll be there.
Gary was your nephew, Bernie.
I'm just trying to find out if
his death was really accidental.
Of course it was an accident.
How do you know?
Because the sheriff said it was.
How do you know
the sheriff's right?
Let me tell you
something, Mr. Matlock.
The sheriff happens to be
a damn good friend of mine.
In fact, he's a damn good
friend to everybody in this town.
And if you think we like the way
you got after him up there today,
you can guess again.
I didn't go after him. I
was going after the truth.
Well, you tried to make him
look like a fool... your own kin.
If you thought you had
any friends left in this town,
you can take my word
for it you've just lost them.
Aah!
You tried to kill me!
You rat bastard!
Could I just interrupt just for
one second? Just for one second?
Feel like talking now?
You were going to send me on
a permanent vacation, all right.
Permanent! Do I
feel like talking?
Yeah, I feel like
talking my head off!
- Hi!
- Hi.
So...
how was your walk?
It was more like a stroll.
A nice, long stroll.
How are you
enjoying my vacation?
With the exception of a couple
of killings, I'm enjoying it fine.
Well, I'm glad one of us is.
Oh, come on. I'll buy you a
cup of coffee and a doughnut.
Oh.
That was Karen
Sylvester. She's real nice.
They all are, actually.
Well, again, at least one of
us has friends in this town.
People are jealous, that's
all. They don't hate you.
Come on.
I'm going to stick
with the brownie,
a great big brownie
with fudge icing that thick,
- and then a jelly doughnut, okay?
- Yeah.
A big jelly doughnut
with powdered sugar.
I see it in there.
Let's just go have toast
and coffee at Aunt Elsie's.
If the world ever runs out of grease,
it's because it's all in your doughnuts!
Shh!
If I lose, I lose,
and if I win, I lose.
Ben, you're doing your best
here under difficult circumstances.
You should be proud of yourself.
- Oh, they hate me.
- They don't.
They hate me, and
I don't give a damn.
Conrad, what are you doing here?
About a half hour ago, I decided
to drive up here this afternoon.
If I had known your aunt was this
great of a cook, I'd have come last night.
Thank you.
Have you got something?
Not something,
Ben... everything.
So, Mr. Anderson, it's
good to have you here today.
Let me ask you this: Does the name
Martin Jensen mean anything to you?
That tattoo you
have on your arm,
he was the tattoo artist who put
it there, wasn't he? Remember?
Maybe you don't want to remember
because you were in prison
at the time, weren't you?
Yes, I was.
What did you do?
Robbed a bank.
A long time ago,
I got in over my head with
some pretty bad dudes.
I made a stupid mistake
and wound up paying for
it with four years of my life.
Hmm.
Is Lucas Anderson
your real name?
No, I changed it when
I got out of prison.
- My name used to be Guy Spellman.
- Uh-huh.
These other two bad dudes,
what were their names?
David Josephs and Bobby Atwater.
Mm-hmm. Would you
mind taking off your coat
and rolling up your sleeve so
the court can see your tattoo?
There you go. Yeah,
yeah, yeah, yeah.
J.A.S.
That stands for Josephs,
Atwater, and Spellman, doesn't it?
Yeah.
Well, what happened
to the other two?
The bad dudes?
I don't know.
Well, the money that you took
from the bank, what happened to it?
I don't know that, either.
Well, how about this?
The three of you hid it,
and then you had the misfortune of being
arrested, convicted, and sent to prison,
and, uh, so you had to just wait
patiently until you were released,
then you recovered it.
No. The other two
might have done that,
but when I got out of
prison I went straight.
Oh, come on. That's where you
got the cash to buy the tavern.
- I told you, I inherited that...
- That was your cut of the take.
You used it to start over here,
just like David Josephs, who
changed his name to James Hamilton,
used his cut to go into
real estate in Atlanta.
No.
But Bobby Atwater was a
different story, wasn't he?
He squandered his,
and 15 years ago,
he showed up here and
threatened to expose your past
and ruin your new life here in
Mt. Harlan unless you paid him off.
So you lured him out in the woods,
and you shot him to death, didn't you?
The body that Max Carter, Noel
Ferguson, and Gary Anderson saw
in the woods that day was
Bobby Atwater's, wasn't it?
- Your Honor!
- You knew...
You knew Noel
had seen your tattoo,
and there was a good chance if
he continued with his research,
he'd uncover your involvement in the
bank robbery and Bobby Atwater's death,
and so you killed
him, too, didn't you?
Oh, come on. Objection!
Mr. Matlock.
Everyone calm down, or I'll
have this courtroom cleared.
From here on out,
you will ask questions...
Relevant questions
about this case...
Do you hear me, Mr. Matlock?
No more speculation.
No more suppositions.
Questions.
And if you don't
understand the difference,
you'll have plenty of time to
learn when I jail you for contempt.
- Understood?
- Yes, sir.
Now get on with it.
Where were you about 5:00 the
day Noel Ferguson was murdered?
Fishing.
Rainbow Creek?
That's a question.
Yeah.
According to Eunice, the
waitress over there at your tavern,
you were gone from
about 3:45 to around 6.
Does that sound about right?
- Yeah.
Did you go by way of
Old Wedgewood Road?
Of course.
Only way you can get to Rainbow
Creek is Old Wedgewood Road?
Well, there's a back
way, but... Go on.
Well, it's kind of roundabout.
It takes a couple of
extra hours to get there.
The thing is they were asphalting
Wedgewood Road that day.
Blocked off a whole half
mile from 6 a.m. to 6 p.m.
Wouldn't let anybody through.
So where did you
really go that day?
I forgot. I did go
the other way.
You couldn't have. You
wouldn't have had time.
You went over Russ
Gifford's house, didn't you?
- No.
- And you stole his knife
and went over to the Mt.
Harlan Motel, didn't you?
And there you stabbed Noel Ferguson
to death to keep your past hidden.
No, I didn't.
You lied about the
creek, the road, fishing,
because you're the
real killer, aren't you?
No, I lied...
I lied because I was at
Jack Sylvester's house.
I was with his wife Karen.
Mrs. Sylvester?
Did she say anything?
I couldn't catch her.
Talk about something
coming out of left field.
Ben, want me to help you wipe that
off... You know, that egg on your face?
Doesn't feel good, does it?
Hi.
- Hi.
- I thought you might want to talk.
Well, to tell you the
truth, I'd really rather not.
How did, uh...?
We're going to work it out.
I'm glad to hear that.
Ahh.
Here, let me help you.
Oh, a bad back?
Yes.
Do you wear a brace?
Yes. I've had to wear that
damn thing for two months.
I have a protruding disc.
I can stand up
or lie flat or walk,
but I can't bend over or sit
longer for than two minutes.
My back went out once.
I thought I'd die, the pain was
always there, like a toothache.
Yes. Yes.
- Well, I... Oh, here.
- Thank you.
I just wanted to drop
by to see how you were.
Um, I'm really...
I'm really sorry.
I, uh... Call me if
you want to talk.
Thank you. Um, I will.
Ben!
What?
I've got it. I've got it!
Yesterday, Lucas
Anderson told the court
that he was with you at the time
Noel Ferguson was murdered.
Is that so?
Yes, it is.
And while he was with you, the
two of you were physically intimate?
Yes.
How long has this been going on?
For about two months.
Huh.
I hear you have a back problem.
- Yes, I do.
- Uh-huh.
Are you getting treatment?
I drive up to Macon
for physical therapy.
Uh-huh.
Well, do you ever talk with your
physical therapist during these sessions?
Yes.
- It's a lady, isn't it?
- Yes.
Did you tell her just last week
that the most annoying
aspect of your back problem
is that you have been unable
to engage in any sexual activity
for, oh, almost three months?
Careful how you
answer, Mrs. Sylvester,
because Ann Weston,
your physical therapist,
is right there on the back row.
And she's all prepared
to take the stand.
So I'll ask you again.
Was Lucas Anderson with
you at the time of the murder?
No.
Do you know where he was?
Why did you lie?
Because I know Lucas,
and he's no murderer.
I just wanted to help.
Nothing further.
Mr. Richardson, do
you wish to cross?
No questions, Your Honor.
Mrs. Sylvester,
you may step down.
Russ!
Hey, Russ!
No. Oh, no, no. Stop.
No. Good dog.
Hey, Russ! Russ!
- Buck, no!
- No.
It's okay, Buck. It's
okay. Good, good dog.
Sit. Sit. Come one. Good
dog. Thatta boy. Thatta boy.
You all right?
Considering how close I came
to being dog food, I'm swell.
Sorry. I was in the bathroom,
and I just heard you a minute ago.
Is he always like that?
He's very territorial.
You mean...
You mean he acts like that
when anybody comes around
the house and you're not here?
Oh, yeah. He won't let
anybody near the house.
You know, we've heard some pretty
confusing testimony around here lately.
First, Lucas perjures himself,
then your wife perjures herself.
What's going on?
How should I know?
It's because you told her to
corroborate Lucas' story, didn't you?
You told her to admit to an
affair that never happened
so that Lucas would have an
alibi for the time of the murder.
That's ridiculous.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
How long have you
known Lucas Anderson?
Fifteen years. Ever since
he moved to Mt. Harlan.
You sure you didn't
know him 20 years ago,
when he and two others robbed
that bank over in Attensburg?
Of course not.
You were an officer of
that bank, weren't you?
- Yes.
- But you didn't know him?
- It was just a coincidence?
- Yes.
Well, what about the, uh...
uh, the Orwell Corporation?
I'm sorry. I don't understand.
The Orwell Corporation?
Yeah, the holding company
that Bobby Atwater, Jim Hamilton, and
Lucas Anderson drew their money out of
when they got out of prison to
start over. You don't remember that?
That beats me. You
were its general partner.
Ahem.
You helped those three
men rob that bank, didn't you?
No.
And then when they got arrested,
you begged them not to
blow the whistle on you.
You promised that you
would invest that money.
It would be waiting for them
when they got out of prison.
And so you formed the Orwell Corporation
as a front for that stolen money.
I did no such thing!
And everything
would have been fine.
No one would have been the
wiser if Noel hadn't showed up.
And he got poking around
in Lucas Anderson's affairs,
and then not only Lucas
was afraid he'd be found out,
but you were afraid
you'd be found out.
So the two of you got
your heads together,
and when the occasion arose,
you both killed him, didn't you?
I did no such... That is a lie,
Mr. Matlock. How dare you?
Objection, Your Honor.
Where is the proof?
Right here. Right here. The
proof's right here, Your Honor.
Let's have it.
This is the knife that
killed Noel Ferguson.
- Do you recognize it?
- No.
Now, Russ told the police that he
keeps his knife on his back porch.
Were you ever on
Russ' back porch?
No, I never had the pleasure.
Russ has a dog... a
Doberman. Did you know that?
No.
Oh, it's a good guard
dog. Good guard dog.
Won't let anybody
near that back porch.
I nearly got bit there
myself yesterday.
Have you ever been
bitten by that dog?
I told you I didn't even
know he had a dog.
Well, you know, that's real odd.
That's interesting.
According to the emergency room
records at Mercy Hospital over in Albany,
you were treated for a dog bite
on your upper left thigh at 7:30 p.m.
on August 18th, the day
Noel Ferguson was killed.
- That does not mean...
- The doctor filled out this form.
He had to. It's the law.
And this is a copy that I received
from the Health Department,
and down here you say that you
were bitten by a large Doberman.
That was kind of dumb.
I'd have lied about that.
- Mr. Matlock.
- Well, Your Honor,
surely he'd have to know somebody
would come after him on that one.
Mr. Matlock.
Yes, sir.
I think that both you and
Lucas Anderson knew
that Noel was somebody
you could not ignore.
And Lucas, knowing
Russ was a real patsy,
lured him away from his job
so he wouldn't have an alibi
for the time of the murder,
while you went over to
Russ' house, stole his knife,
and got bit in the process.
Then one or both of you
went over to Noel's motel
and stabbed him to death and
left the knife to incriminate Russ.
Then you went over to Albany
to get your dog bite taken care of
because you couldn't do it
here because everybody...
Because everybody
knows now anyway.
The bank robbery 20 years ago,
the Orwell Corporation,
the lie your wife
told on the stand,
the dog bite...
all coincidences?
I don't think so,
and I seriously doubt
that they do, either.
Ladies and gentlemen of the
jury, have you reached a verdict?
We have, Your Honor.
We find the defendant,
Russell Gifford,
not guilty.
Thank you, one and all.
This court is adjourned.
You're welcome back
anytime, both of you.
Next time you're here,
you can do it in the gazebo.
Do what?
Get married.
We'll keep that in mind.
Thank you for
everything, Uncle Ben.
You don't know how
much I appreciate it.
A pleasure.
Well, we had a good time.
Bye.
Thank you.
Hey, Harley.
Hello, Ben.
A neighbor of Gary Adler's said
he saw Lucas talking to
Gary out back by his truck
about 20 minutes before
we found him in the ditch,
and the lab found traces of blood on
a wrench we took out of Lucas' van.
You going to press charges?
Yep.
Thought you ought to know.
Tell you what, Harley.
Next time I come back
here, let's just go fishing.
Let's do that.
I'll see you.
You surprise me, Ben.
I expected you to make a fool of yourself
in court, but you got away with it.
Oh, well, thank you, Lucy.
You're rich, you're famous.
Well, that's what they say.
You still play the ukulele?
Every chance I get.
I figured.
Still like hotdogs?
Sure do.
I hate hotdogs.
I know you do, Lucy.
I'm glad I never
married you, Ben.
I'm glad you're glad, Lucy.
Come on, Billy.
What's that?
A five spot.
Look at it this way, Ben.
You've got a successful
law practice in Atlanta.
You've got a brand-new
five spot in your hand.
You're a free man.
And I've got Lucy.
Count your blessings.
Come on, Billy!
- Bye.
Bye.
What are you doing?
Counting my blessings.
- Bye.
www.tvsubtitles.net